Guide to the Wilbur Daniel Steele Papers, 1907-1970 M0019
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wilbur Daniel Steele papers
1907-1970
M0019
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
7.0 Linear feet
Steele, Wilbur Daniel, 1886-1970
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. J. F. Jenners and Wilbur D. Steele, 1961, Peter Steele, 1988, David Jenness, 1989, and some additions from other sources.
Biographical Note
Wilbur Daniel Steele was born in 1886 in Greensboro, N.C. His father became Professor in Iliff School of Theology and University of Denver in 1893 where Wilbur D. Steele had his early education and later won a two year scholarship to the University of Denver where he was active in athletics.
His love of art brought him to Boston where he attended the school of fine arts attached to the Boston Museum. He showed great promise in art, but began to write short stories.
In 1913 he married Margaret Thurston who was a talented painter. They had two sons. In 1931 Mrs. Steele died.
In 1932 he married Norma Mitchell, an actress and playwright with whom he collaborated on several plays. They make their home at Lynne, Connecticut where they still reside.
He was several times winner of the coveted O. Henry Short Story Prize. He traveled widely in Africa and Europe, basing many of his stories from various places he lived or visited.
1886 Born Mar. 17, Greensboro, N.C. (of damyankee parents).
1890-1892 Binney's Compend of Theology.
1893-1907 Grade, Prep & College (A.B.), University Park, Denver. Letters in 5 sports, captain in 2.
1907-1908 Boston Museum of Fine Arts (school attached to same)
1908-1909 Paris, various art courses - began writing there & in Italy.
1909-1920 Provincetown, Mass. Co-founder of Provincetown Players. Married Margaret Thurston, 1913 - sons, Thurston, `15, Peter, `18 - and during this period, following breaks.
1917 Travel (for Harpers Mag.) in lesser Antilles & Demarara.
1918 Correspondent, attached to Navy, for Cosmopolitan Mag., Eng., Ireland & France.
1919-1920 Bermuda
1920-1922 North Africa (for Harpers) Riviera & England.
1922 Removed from Provincetown to Nantucket - resided there until `29 -- during which following breaks (winters):
1922-1923 So. Norwalk, Conn. 23-4, France. 24-5, Westport, Conn. 25-6, Switzerland. 26-7 & 27-8, Charleston, S.C. (There's a winter missing, be dogged if I know where.)
1929 Removed from Nantucket. 29-31, Chapel Hill, N.C. Wife, Margaret, died there.
1932 Married Norma Mitchell (actress & playwright) in London -- removed to her home (then new) in country neighboring Lyme, Conn. Resided there ever since. With following breaks: winters: 32-33 & 33-4, Hollywood (very sad) 34-5 35-6 & 38-9, N.Y.C. 39-40, Hollywood (still sadder). 1944, I made extended trip around South America, flying.
Both my sons are now married, with children, boys.
Both graduated from Brown Univ.
Scope and Content
Includes correspondence, chiefly letters by Steele to various members of his family, manuscripts of numerous short stories, plays and novels, three etchings done by Steele, 1908, the privately printed story, "A Life," publishers agreements, photographs, press releases, clippings and other papers.
General note
ms. and/or article at Stanford.
General note
(more or less complete) fairly chronological.
General note
Notations: Number underlined: has been published (as, 12)
*, I have it filed in a clipping as published
#, I have it filed in manuscript
?, doubtful, as of scripts untitled & unremembered
C, I have it in a published collection of my own work
A, I have it in a published anthology.
Periodicals & dates of publication given where able Dates of writing, following titles, will be vague.
No notation, means never sold or published, or ppreserved. All other than Short Stories, thus (12)
- CORRESPONDENCE IN FOLDER OF PHOTOGRAPHS OF STEELE, HIS FAMILY, SOME OF HIS ART WORK. In People photo file (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. Margaret Steele W. Family, Mar 8, 1913.
  - 2. Edward J. O'Brien, Feb 3, 1916.
  - 3. Edward J. O'Brien, May 23, 1916.
  - 4. Maxton Bryan, Sep 13, 1916.
  - 5. George Broadhurst, Apr 22, 1921.
  - 6. A.E. Coppard, Dec 10, 1921.
  - 7. Clarice E. Richards, Dec 13, 1921.
  - 8. Nellie M. Rowe, Oct 2, 1922.
  - 9. Blanche Colton Williams, Oct 6, 1922.
  - 10. B.P. Schulberg, Jan 29, 1923.
  - 11. Samuel E. Morison, Mar 2, 1923.
  - 12. Beulah Steele Jenness, Aug 24, 1923.
  - 13. Katharine Fuller Gerould, Jul 27, 1924.
  - 14. John A. Lawlor, Oct 4, 1924.
  - 15. Marie A. Belloc [UNK], Nov 11, 1933.
  - 16. Edward Poor Montgomery, Jul 12, 1933.
  - 17. Martin J. Chicoine, Jan 27, 1934.
  - 18. Thurston Steele, Mar 11, 1934.
  - 19. Kenneth Macgowan, Apr 6, 1934.
  - 20. Muriel Steele Hunter, Jun 11, 1944.
  - 21. Vilhjalmu Stefansson, Jun 20, 1944.
  - 22. Luther Blake, Jun 20, 1945.
  - 23. Beulah Steele Jenness, Jul 1, 1945.
  - 24. Luther?, Jul 4, 1945.
  - 25. Harold Matson, Jul 30, 1945.
  - 26. Harold Matson, Aug 1, 1945.
  - 27. Jasper Spock, Aug 13, 1945.
  - 28. James T. Babb, Oct 29, 1948.
  - 29. A.F. Raiter, Jr., Sep 16, 1953.
  - 30. Hugh Peyton, Sep 23, 1953.
  - 31. Hugh Peyton, Oct 6, 1953.
  - 32. James A. Pryde, Nov 4, 1953.
- UNDATED LETTERS, NOTES (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. Note written by W.D.S., May?, 1914.
  - 2. Mrs. W.D. Steele to Beulah S. Jennes, Aug 17,?
  - 3. Notes from Arthur Bullard
  - 4. [George Ctam Cook] Chaotic note to W.D.S. (?), Undated
  - 5. Robert Garland
  - 6. Mary Ellen Norwood, N.D.
  - 7. Edward J. O'Brien, N.D.
  - 8. Mary Ellen Norwood, N.D.
  - 9. Margaret Steele, Mar 20,?
  - 10. Margaret Steele, N.D.
  - 11. Margaret Steele, 7 Jan?
  - 12. John W. Vandercook
- CORRESPONDENCE OUT (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Family Letters, May 4, 1907 - Jan 24, 1910.
  - Family Letters, Feb 13, 1910 - Nov 27, 1910. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Family Letters, Dec 12, 1910 - Jul 29, 1912. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Family Letters, Aug 16, 1912 - Dec 31, 1915. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Family Letters, Feb 23, 1916 - Apr 22, 1918. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Family Letters, Oct 27, 1918 - Jun 25, 1920. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Family Letters, Jul 22, 1920 - Mar 19, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Family Letters, Nov 18, 1925 - Oct 1, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Family Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript story by Muriel Steele Hunter (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - LETTERS, to MURIEL STEELE HUNTER, 1910-1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Account book of prices paid literary works (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Press Notices (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Press Notices (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Clippings - CLIPS ADDED, 5/68 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Short Stories A - C. (Box 3, Folder 1-43)
    Arrangement note
    [Alphabetically arranged]
  - Short Stories: D - G. (Box 4, Folder 1-36)
  - Short Stories: H - L. (Box 5, Folder 1-34)
  - Short Stories: M - R. (Box 6, Folder 1-40)
  - Short Stories: S - Y. (Box 7, Folder 1-37)
  - Novel [manuscript] That Girl From Memphis. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Novel [manuscript] Isles of the Blest. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Plays: Dragon's Teeth (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - How Beautiful With Shoes (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Any Woman and a later version P/ft. Alta Calif Bookstore, Sept, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Any Woman (2d draft) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Diamond Wedding (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The Giant's Star (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Contemporaries (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ropes (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - John Addam (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - When Hell Froze (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - This Day Between (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Post Road (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Novel draft: The Way To The Gold. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Unifinished novel: Down Stream. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Odds and ends (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Taxes, receipts (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Publishers agreements (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Scraps (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Unknown (Box 10, Folder 7-11)
  - Story: That Girl from Memphis. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- 1 THE STRING, (1908-9)
- 2? AN APOSTLE OF BROTHERLY LOVE, (1908)
- 3 UNCLE LEMUEL, (1908)
- 4 (?)# THE OLD MAN'S BROTHER, (1908-9)
  Scope and Contents note
  Sold to McClures, but never pub'd, I believe.
- 5 # THE TIDE, (1909)
- 6 * ON THE EBB TIDE, (1909-10)
  Success Mag. June, 1910
- 7 *# GLOOMY ON THE GRIDIRON (THE INTELLECTUAL GREEK), (1910)
  Success Mag. Nov. 1910
- 8 # THE NIGHT COUNTRY, (1911?)
- (9) # OUR PEACE NAVY (non-fiction), (1911?)
  (I am fairly sure this was never sold or pub'd)
- 10 THE MOVING PICTURE MAGNATE
- 11 # THE SENTIMENTAL FLYING DUTCHMAN, (1911-12)
  Pub'd, I believe in Adventure Mag., 1912-13.
- 12 SALT OF THE EARTH
- 13 TREASURE TROVE
- 14 FAIRCHILD?USCGS, (1911?)
- 15 NATIONAL AIRS, Inc., (1911?)
  (May possibly have been rewritten as PICKLED SUNSHINE)
- 16 * THE ADMIRABLE ADMIRALS, (1911)
  Success Magazine, 1911(?)
- 17 * PICKLED SUNSHINE (PHOEBUS BOUND), (1911)
  National Magazine, June, 1911.
- (18) # CLOTHES AND THE MAN, (1911)
  (A novel, very punk, never sold)
- 19 * THE INSURRECTO, (1911)
  National Magazine, May, 1911
- 20 *# THE ISLANDERS, (1911)
  Harpers, 1911-12 (?)
- (21) FISH WEIRS
- 22 (?) AN EYE FOR AN EYE
- 23 CAPTAIN NAPOLIAN BONAPART SMALL
- 24 * THE YOUNGER TWIN, (1912-3-4 various versions)
  Harpers, 1914 (Had previously appeared without my knowledge in New Story Mag (?) Hell to pay.)
- 25 CONDOR
- 26 AN OFFICER BORN, (1911)
  American Magazine, 1912
- 27 C A WHITE HORSE WINTER, (1911-12)
  Atlantic Monthly, 1912
- 28 THE STONE MAN, (1912?)
  Adventure, 1913
- 29 # THE SCHOOLHOUSE, (1913?)
- 30 * THUMBS DOWN, (1913?)
  Harpers Weekly (?)
- 31 # ORPHEUS O'GRADY, (1913)
- ( 32) * THE PRICE OF FISH, (1912-13?)
  Metropolitan Mag. 1912-13 (?)
- 33 * THE HANDKERCHIEF LADY'S GIRL (FAIR NAMES), (1913)
  Harpers, Feb. 1914
- ( 34) * THE MOVING PICTURE MACHINE IN THE JUNGLE (The Wild Animal Game), (1913)
  McClures, 1913.
- 35 * AN EYE OF THE PEOPLE, (1912?)
  Illustrated Sunday Magazine, May, 1913
- 36 * PA-JIM, (1914)
  Scribners, Nov. 1914
- 37 * THE WICKEDNESS OF FATHER VEIERA (WHAT FATHER VEIERA SAW), (1913?)
  Atlantic, 1914, July
- 38 * CAPTAIN ULYSSES G. DADD (retired), (1914)
  Scribners, 1914, July
- 39 THE WRECK OF THE QUEEN ETC., (1914?)
- 40 THE BOOK OF ILLUSION
- 41 * A MATTER OF EDUCATION, ([UNK])
  Harpers May, 1915
- 42 * C THE KILLER'S SON, (1914?)
  Harpers, 1914(?)
- 43 * THE MIRACLE, (1914)
  The Masses 1915, January
- 44 # THE WEAKNESS OF THE FLESH, (1914?)
- 45 C A THE YELLOW CAT, (1914)
  Harpers, 1915, March
- 46 * HERITAGE, (1914)
  Harpers, July 1915
- 47 * ON MOON HILL, (1914)
  Century, April, 1915
- 48 # THE TEMPTATION OF FATHER VEIERA, (1914)
- 49 SAL'S YEAR
- 50 * C# ROMANCE, (1914)
  Atlantic, June, 1915
- 51 THE MAN WHO FORGOT HIS PLACE
- 52 * THE REAL THING, (1915)
  Century, May 1915
- 53 * THE FREE AGENT, (1915)
  Colliers, July 17, 1915
- 54 C # A DEVIL OF A FELLOW, (1915)
  Seven Arts Mag. 1917, April
- 55 * AN ESCAPE FROM FREEDOM (BEACH COTTAGES), (1915-16?)
  Harpers, Oct. 1916
- 56 # BABY DOLL, (1916?)
- 57 WOLF, WOLF
- 58 C*A# DOWN ON THEIR KNEES, (1915)
  Harpers, July 1916
- 59 * # THE LAST FLETCHER, (1916?)
  Good Housekeeping, Sept. 1916
- 60 * # BEFORE THE MAST, (1915)
  Harpers, March, 1916
- 61 C LAND'S END, (1915)
  Colliers, March 25, 1916
- 62 # THE CUCKOO'S YOUNG, (1915?)
- 63 # LITTLE BROTHER, (1915?)
- 64 C WHITE HANDS, (1916)
  Pictorial Review, Jan. 1917
- 65 * THE HALF GHOST (LEGS), (1916)
  Harpers, July 1917
- 66 FREE, (1916)
  Century, Aug. 1917
- ( 67) * THE KILLERS OF PROVINCETOWN, (1916)
  Harpers, March, 1917
- 68 C#A CHING, CHING, CHINAMAN, (1917)
  Pict. Review, June, 1917
- 69 * MR. TIMMONS TACKLES LIFE (TAME OATS), (1916)
  A three-part serial in Harpers, 1916-7-8 (???)
- 70 * C KED'S HAND, (1916?)
  Harpers, Sept. 1917
- 71 C THE WAGES OF SIN, (1917?)
  Pict. Review, March 1918
- 72 * # Eternal Youth, (1917?)
  Scribners, April 1918
- 73 * A POINT OF HONOR, (1917?)
  Harpers, Nov. 1917
- 74) *# AT THE OCEAN CROSS ROADS, (1917)
  Harpers, Oct. 1917
- 75) # ENTERTAINMENT FOR MAN & BIRD (MAN AND BIRD)
  ????
- 76 C # THE WOMAN AT SEVEN BROTHERS, (1917)
  Harpers, Dec. 1917
- 77) *# BELEAGUERED ISLAND, THE, (1917)
  Harpers, May, 1918
- 78 C*# THE WHITE MAN, (1917)
  Harpers, Feb. 1918
- 79 #* YOU'RE RIGHT AT THAT, (1917)
  Colliers, Feb.23,1918
- 80 C* ALWAYS SUMMER, (1917)
  Harpers, April, 1918
- 81 C# A MAN'S A FOOL, (1918)
  Metropolitan, June, 1918
- 82 * # THE PERFECT FACE, (1918)
  Harpers, August, 1918
- 83 C * FOR WHERE IS YOUR FORTUNE NOW, (1918)
  Pict. Review, Nov. 1918
- 84 A*# THE DARK HOUR, (1918)
  Atlantic, May 1918 (reprinted in same 1940(?))
- 85 *# MR. SCATTERGOOD & THE OTHER WORLD, (1918)
  Harpers, July 1918
- 86 * A TASTE OF THE OLD BOY, (1918)
  Colliers, Sept.28,1918
- 87 * THE HEART OF A WOMAN, (1918)
  Harpers, Feb. 1919
- (88) TURNING BACK TO THE SEA, (1918)
  On assignment for Cosmopolitan, never pub'd, though paid
- ( 89) * CONTACT, (1918)
  Harpers, 1819
- 90 * GOODFELLOW
  Harpers, April 1919
- 91 C*A FOR THEY KNOW NOT WHAT THEY DO, (1919)
  Pict. Review, July, 1919
- 92 C # Luck, (1919)
  Harpers, Aug. 1919
- 93 C*# LA GUIABLESSE
  Harpers, Sept. 1919
- 94 * # ACCOMPLICE AFTER THE FACT, (1919)
  Good Housekeeping, Aug. 1919
- 95 C*A# OUT OF EXILE, (1919)
  Pict. Review, Nov. 1919
- 96 # LIGHTNING, (1919)
  Noted as sold to Colliers 1919, no record of publishing
- 97 * CLAY AND THE CLOVEN HOOF, (1919)
  Harper, 2 parts, Oct-Nov, 1919
- 98 *# GOD'S MERCY, (1919)
  Pict. Review, two part, Jul-Aug 1920
- 99 C* BOTH JUDGE AND JURY, (1919)
  Harpers, Jan. 1920
- 100 C*A FOOTFALLS, (1919)
  Pict. Review, Oct. 1920
- 101 C* A LIFE, (1919)
  Pictorial Review August, 1921
- 102 # THE ADVENTURE OF THE MISSING LINKS, (1920)
- 103 * Toinette of Maisonnoire, (1920)
  Pict. Review, July 1921
- 104 * C# AT TWO IN THE BUSH, (1920)
  Harpers, Oct. 1920
- 105 C* THE SHAME DANCE, (1920)
  Harpers, Dec. 1920
- 106 * FOULED ANCHOR, (1920)
  Harpers, April 1921
- 107 C* ROPES (a one-act play), (1920)
  Pictorial Review, 1920?
- 108) * A COMMUTER IN BARBARY, (1920)
  Happers 1920-21?
  General note
  Nos. 108-9-10-11-12 were travel scetches for Harpers.
- 109) THE FOURTH PILLAR
  ditto
- 110) THE MEDENINE ROAD
- ( 111) IN THE MOUNTAINS OF THE DESERT
- ( 112) IN THE MZAB
- 113 CA THE MARRIAGE IN KAIRWAN (OH), (1921)
  Harpers, Dec. 1921
- 114 C HE THAT HIDETH HIS SECRET, (1921)
  Harpers, 1922, Feb.
- 115 CA FROM THE OTHER SIDE OF THE SOUTH (OB), (1921)
  Pict. Review, Aug.1922
- 116 C* ARAB STUFF, (1921)
  Harpers, Jan 1923
- 117 * C THE MAD, (1921)
  Pict. Review, July, 1922
- 118 CA THE GIANTS' STAIR (a one-act play), (1921)
  Pictorial Review 1922?
- 119 THE MAN WHO SAT, (1921)
- 120 * MARRIAGE, (1921?)
  Pict. Review, Aug. 1924
- 121 C* CROCUSES, (1922)
  Pict. Review, May, 1923
- 122 C* THE ANGLO SAXON, (1922)
  Harpers, Aug. 1922
- 123 * THE FIRST BORN, (1922)
  Pict. Review, Dec. 1922
- 124 * GINGER BEER, (1922)
  Pict. Review, Nov. 1923
- 125 # IN THE CITY OF THE REVOLUTION, (1922)
- 126 # ANOTHER PEOPLE, (1922)
  Pict. Review, 1923-4(?)
- 127 C# TOWER OF SAND, (1922)
- 128 C# LOST-AT-SEA, (1922)
  Pict. Review (as above?)
- 129 # BLESSED ARE THE POOR, (1923)
  Bought by Pict.Review, but never published.
- 130 *# THE THINKER, (1923)
  Pictorial Review, Dec. 1924
- 131 C*A WHAT DO YOU MEAN, AMERICANS (OH), (23)
  Pictorial Review, April, 1924
- 132 * NOW I LAY ME, (1923)
  Pict. Review, April, 1926
- 133 C SOOTH, (1924?)
  Pict. Review, 1924 (?)
- 134 A MOTHER'S LOVE, (1924)
  Pict. Review, (????)
- 135 C*A SIX DOLLARS (OB), (1924)
  Pict. Review, March, 1925
- 136 C* THE TERRIBLE WOMAN (one-cat play), (1924)
  Pict. Review, 1925(?)
- 137 # VIRTUE, (1924)
  Bought by Pict. Review, but never published
- 138 C*A WHEN HELL FROZE (HPS), (1924)
  Harpers, May, 1925
- 139 C*A BLUE MURDER (WBS, etc), (1924)
  Harpers, Oct. 1925
- 140 C*A THE MAN WHO SAW THROUGH HEAVEN (OH), (1925)
  Harpers, Sept. 1925
- 141 C*A OUT OF THE WIND (OB), (1925)
  Pict. Review, Oct. 1925
- 142 *# BEAUTY, (1925)
  Good Housekeeping, Jan.1926
- 143 C [UNK], (1925)
  Pict. Review, Aug. 1926
- 144 *# BROTHER'S KEEPER, (1925)
  Harper's, Dec. 1925
- 145 C*# AUTUMN BLOOM, (1926)
  Pictorial Review, Nov. 1926
- 146 * GRAY GOOSE, (1926) (or'25?)
  Harpers, March, 1926
- 147 C*# MARY DRAKE AND WILL TODD, (1926)
  Pict. Review (2 parts) March, April, 1928
- 148 C*A BUBBLES (OH), (1926)
  Harpers, Aug. 1926
- 149 * AN AMERICAN COMEDY, (1926)
  Pict. Review, Oct. 1927
- 150 * NEW DEAL, (1926)
  Scribners, 1927-8 (?)
- 151 C*# A DRINK OF WATER, (1926)
  Harpers, 1926-7(?)
- 152 # PLAYTHINGS, (1926)
- 153 *# SPEED, (1926)
  Pict. Review, Aug. 1927
- 154 *# WIFE OF A VIKING, (1927)
  Pict. Review, April 1930
- 155 C SAILOR? SAILOR, (1927)
  Pict. Review, 1927-8-9 (?)
- 156 (THE BAD GIRL), (1927)
  Pict. Review, 1927 (?)
- 157 *# WINTER WHEAT, (1927)
  Pict. Review, Sept. 1928
- 158 C*# NEVER ANYTHING THAT FADES, (1928)
  Harpers, 1928-9- (?)
- 159 A* THE SILVER SWORD (OH), (1928)
  Pict. Review, march, 1929
- 160 # SATAN AM A SNAKE, (1928)
  Harpers, 1928-9 (?)
- 161 * SURPRIZE, (1928)
  Pict. Review, Sept 1929
- 162 * SURVIVOR, (1928)
  Pict. Review, May 1929
- 163 * CONJUH, (1928)
  Pict. Review, Oct 1929
- 164 # A CAN'T CROSS JORDAN BY MYSELF (OH), (1929)
  Pict. Review, 1930-1-?
- 165 * QUICKSILVER, (1929)
  Harpers, 1929-30 (?)
- 166 *# DAUGHTER OF THE SOIL, (1929)
  Pict. Review, March, 1931
- 167 *# A PIONEERS, (1929)
  Harpers, 1929-30(?)
- 168 * KI (`TWEEN RIVERS), (1929)
  Pict. Review, Feb. 1930
- 169 *# CONSCIENCE (TWO SECONDS), (1929)
  Pict. Review, Jan. 1932
- 170 # IN THE SHADE OF THE TREE, (1929)
  Harpers, 1929-31 (?)
- 171 *# DIAMOND WEDDING, (1929)
  Womans Home Comp., Sept. 1930
- 172 # THE GULF, (1929?)
- 173 * GREEN VIGIL, (1930)
  L.H.J., Nov. 1930
- 174 *# LIGHT, (1930)
  L.H.J., Nov., 1930)
- 175 # RENEGADE, (1930)
  L.H.J., 1930-1 (?)
- 176 *# THE HILLS OF HEAVEN, (1930)
  Good Housekeeping, Jan. 1931
- 177 *# A THE BODY OF THE CRIME, (1930)
  L.H.J., 1930-1(?)
- 178 # MAN WITHOUT A GOD (BRUISED GRAIN) (TOWN DRUNK), (1931)
  L.H.J. (2 parts) 1931(?)
- 179 # WILL AND BILL, (1931)
  L.H.J., 1931-2(?)
- 180 # TWENTY*SEVEN MINUTES, (1931)
- 181 * WHERE THERE'S SMOKE, (1931)
  L.H.J., Oct. 1932
- 182 # THOUSAND HORSEPOWER, (1931)
- 183 # BY APPOINTMENT, (1932)
  Sat Eve Post, 1932-3 (?)
- 184 # A HOW BEAUTIFUL WITH SHOES (OB), (1932)
  Harpers, 1932-3 (?)
- 185 IN MEMORIAM, (1932)
  L.H.J., 1932-3-4 (???)
- 186 # SOMEBODY, (1932-3?)
  Harpers Bazaar, 1933(?)
- 187 # I'LL DANCE TO MUSIC, (1933?)
- 188 # BIG DAY, (1933)
  Chicago Tribune 1933-4-?
- 189 # RED CARPET ON THE FLOOR, (1934?)
  Herald-Tribune (This Week) 1933-4-?
- 190 # A BATH IN THE SEA, (1934?)
  Life Story Mag. - to be published in 1946
- 191 LANDFALL (A SHIP ON THE OCEAN???), (1934?)
  Liberty (???)
- 192 # DUE NORTH, (1934?)
  Cosmopolitan 1934-5-?
- 193 # ROPE ENOUGH
- 194 NOT A CHANCE
- 195 # DUMB COP
- 196 # JEOPARDY
- 197 # MOONSHINE & SIXPENCE (Revised ADVENTURE OF MISSING LINKS)
- 198 # THE UNCLE PROBLEM
- 199 # THE LIGHTS ARE OUT
- 200 # HOW MANY EVER DID, (1938)
- 201 #* BAPTISM, (1938)
  Good Housekeeping, 1939(?)
- 202 THE BLACK ROAD, (1939)
  Colliers 1939 (?)
- 203 (pub'd title?) (NOTHING ON HIM), (1939)
  Colliers, 1939(?)
- 204 # WILL YOU ASK ME TO DANCE, (1939)
- 205 * ISLES OF SPICE AND LILIES, (1929)
  Atlantic, 1940
- 206 # A WAY WITH WOMEN, (1939)
- 207 # THE DAY LOU GEHRIG BENCHED HIMSELF (HANG ONTO HEAVEN), (1939)
- 208 * A LIFE IS SO LITTLE, (1940)
  Good Housekeeping, Oct. 1940
- 209 # NABOB, (1940)
- 210 # THE GOLDEN AGE, (1940)
- 211 # THE PINMALLOW PLACE, (1940)
- 212 # LADY ADDIE, (1941)
- 213 # NICE GOING, (1941)
- 214 THE GOOD LIFE, (1941)
  Womans Home Comp. 1941 (?)
- 215 (SPLENDID GARMENTS), (1943)
  Cosmopolitan 1943
- 216 THE CROWNING DIVORCE CASE, (1943)
  Cosmopolitan, (1943(?)
- 217 THE CRYSTAL GAZER'S DAUGHTER, (1943)
  Good Housekeeping, 1943-4 (?)
- 218 * THE BOSTON STORY, (1943)
  Aug. 1939 Cosmopolitan
- 219 # HER SOUL HER OWN, (1943)
- 220 # STARS OVER THE SILVER RIVER, (1944)
- 221 # ALONE WITH RUBY, (1944)
- 222 * DEEP WATERS (AND PRESUMED LOST), (1944)
  Life Story, Aug. 1945
- 223 # THE FAMOUS MILE, (1944)
- 224 # THE BUILDING OF THE SHIP, (1945)